Guide to the Western United States business records, 1860-1920 JL005
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Western United States business records,
1860-1920
JL005
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
45.0 Items
Scope and Content
These records are a miscellaneous collection of ledgers, journals, cash books, letter books, stock books, certificates, and daybooks, as well as a folder of deeds to mining and other property in Carson and Virginia cities, Nevada, by Mrs. Margaret A. Ormsby, grandmother of the donor, Mr. Willard O. Wayman. (The entire collection is dated 1860-1920)
Provenance
Donors unknown except for the Wayman-Ormsby Papers, which were a gift of Willard O. Wayman, 1940 to Jackson Library. Transferred from Jackson Library, ca. 1979.
Access Restrictions
None.
- C.E. Parton, sundry ledger, 1911-1912 (Volume 1)
- C.E. Parton, cash ledger, 1907-1909 (Volume 2)
- C.E. Parton, cash ledger, 1909-1911 (Volume 3)
- C.E. Parton, ledger, 1907-1910 (Volume 4)
- Atlantic Portland Cement Co., journal, 1906-1910 (Volume 5)
- Atlantic Portland Cement Co., cash, 1906-1908 (Volume 6)
- Atlantic Portland Cement Co., journal, 1906-1907 (Volume 7)
- Atlantic Portland Cement Co., journal, 1908 (Volume 8)
- Atlantic Portland Cement Co., stock certificates (samples) (Box 9, Volume a)
- Atlantic Portland Cement Co., transfer journal, 1906- (Box 9, Volume b)
- Atlantic Portland Cement Co., letter book, 1908-1909 (Box 9, Volume c)
- Atlantic Portland Cement Co., letter book, 1909-1910 (Box 10, Volume a)
- Pavilion Skating Rink Co., minute book, 1906-1916 (Box 10, Volume b)
- Pacific Sulphur and Chemical Co., stock book, 1920's (Box 10, Volume c)
- Wine Grape [Co.], cash book (Box 10, Volume d)
- Northwestern Portland Cement Co., record, 1906-1907 (Box 10, Volume e)
- M.K. Blake Estate Co., record, 1907 (Box 10, Volume f)
- Outstanding Coin book, 1907-1908 (Box 11, Volume a)
- P.& S. book, 1909-1910 (Box 11, Volume b)
- Wayman and Ormsby deeds, 1860-1877 (Box 11, Volume c)
  General note
  Scope and Contents note
  (Papers belonging to Mrs. Margaret A. Ormsby, a citizen of Virginia City, Nevada; the widow of Major W.M. Ormsby who was killed in an Indian fight with Chief Winnemuca in 1860. Papers consist largely of deeds to mining and other property in Carson and Virginia Cities, Nevada).
- Unidentified daybooks, 1909 and 1911 (Volume 12-13)
- G.M.B. journal, 1877-1878 (Volume 14)
- G.M.B. ledger, 1877-1878 (Volume 15)